Shibin Thomas Stanley Paul

Address: Meitnerweg 4, 44227 Dortmund,

Germany

Email: sshibinthomass@gmail.com

Phone: +49 15566440790

LinkedIn: <u>/sshibinthomass</u>
Github: <u>/sshibinthomass</u>

Portfolio: https://sshibinthomass

.github.io/myportfolio/



Profile

I am currently pursuing a Master's degree in Automation and Robotics with a focus on Cognitive Systems, and I am excited about contributing to VR and AR applications. I have experience in C#, and have worked with Unity on various projects. My creativity, ability to work and strong communication skills make me well-suited for this role. Additionally, I have knowledge of 3D modeling and texturing using Blender. I am enthusiastic about the opportunity to bring my skills and passion to your team.

Education

M.S Automation and Robotics (2023-Present)

TU Dortmund | Dortmund, Germany | Current CGPA- 1.90

B.E Mechatronics (2018-2022)

Sri Krishna College of Engineering and Technology | India | CGPA- 1.45

Academic Excellence Award 2018-2019 Outstanding Project Award 2020-2021

Work Experience

Vuram Hyper-automation Services (Jun 2021 – Oct 2023)

- -Technical Consultant | Apr 2023 Oct 2023
- -Associate Technical Consultant | Jul 2022 April 2023
- -Intern | Jun 2021 Jun 2022
- Led a cross-functional team of 5 in deploying innovative AI-driven applications, collaborating with clients and the R&D team, resulting in a 20% improvement in overall process efficiency.
- Collaborated closely with business experts and stakeholders to implement advanced AI and NLP solutions, significantly enhancing the functionality of products for 2 key clients.
- Worked on implementing a chatbot using NLP technology in Appian, improving user interaction and support response time by 30% for better customer satisfaction.

Recognized as spotlight of the month twice in just 1 year.

DeepvisionTech | Intern (Jan 2020 – Jul 2020)

- Collected and processed satellite data for ML model to improved crop health monitoring by 20%.
- Utilized CNN models for image analysis, enhancing the platform's ability to predict crop diseases with over 85% accuracy

Publications

Development of Mobile App using AR for E-education and Training Systems

Uses 3D visuals in augmented reality to enhance understanding of complex STEM concepts, providing interactive, offline or online learning for improved knowledge retention.

Technology in Design Aspect of BIN Bot Robot - IEEE

Engineered a robotic system utilizing TensorFlow, Servo and DC motors powered by Raspberry Pi to mitigate the spread of disease within institutions and industries.

Patent

Handheld Device for Detecting Quality of Eggs (Application No. 202141014712 A)

Utilized machine learning to analyse data on factors such as temperature, weight loss, color, thickness, shell strength, eggshell cracks, blood spots, porosity, and air cell depth, improving egg quality assessment accuracy by 20% and enhancing expiration date prediction by 15%.

Projects

YogaVision (IOT-based VR Application)

Designed, animated, and engineered a VR yoga App with pulse and BPM sensors, integrating cloud services for real-time health tracking, reducing stress, and enhancing user engagement by 25%.

SafeMate (Employee Management and Surveillance Bot)

Developed and deployed a Raspberry Pi-based workplace safety system using facial recognition, mask detection, voice interaction, and anomaly detection, improving compliance and security monitoring for about 50 employees by up to 40%.

Virtual Reality Under Water Museum

Created a VR Underwater Museum for immersive exploration of marine life and artifacts.

Virtual Training for Employees

Developed a VR Training platform for employees, enhancing skills through interactive simulations.

Augmented Reality Car Museum

Created an AR Car Museum, offering interactive experiences with modern vehicles.

Achievements

- Received TNSCST Best Project Award from the Government of Tamil Nadu.
- Secured 1st place in the Smart India Hackathon organized by the Government of India.
- Earned 1st place in SAE Tier 2 for App development and cloud computing.
- Won 1st place in the Engineers Day Expo hosted by SKCET in 2019 and 2022.
- Attained 3rd place in the TCS XR Pro Hackathon by CII Connect and TCS.
- Achieved 3rd place in the IFA IOT Hackathon, themed 'IOT for All'.

Certifications

- Introduction to Augmented Reality and AR Core | Coursera
- Deep Learning Specialization (5 courses) | Coursera
- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, ML, and DL | Coursera
- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) | Coursera

Additional Skills

Technical Skills

Extended Reality

- Unity, Blender (Animation)
- AR (AR Core, Vuforia, AR Foundation)
- VR (Google VR, Oculus SDK)

Python, (C# Unity)

ML/DL (Tensorflow, Pytorch, Sklearn, Keras)

Misc (Django, Selenium, OpenCV)

Languages

- English- Full Professional
- Deutsch- Limited Working
- Tamil- Native/ Bilingual
- French- Elementary